

PROFILE

General Manager for Infrastructure and Systems with proven experience in Hospitality Industry for 16 years, with a warm and friendly demeanor always. Punctual problem solver and avid multitasker. Track record of being an essential part of the management team (pre-opening and post-opening) in providing effective solutions that produce immediate impact and contribute to the Hotel's long-term success.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+639173016146 +14075308922

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/leningonzalez-81b864a0/

EMAIL:

<u>lenin.gonzalez@gmail.com</u>

OTHER INFO

347 M. Vicente Street. Dansalan Gardens, Mandaluyong City, Philippines September 25, 1976 Nicaraguan Citizen with Permanent Philippines Resident Visa 13(A) ACR#F0000200948

LENIN GONZALEZ

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Manager IT Infrastructure and Systems Vanguard Hotels Pte. Ltd September 2020 –Present Group IT Manager Vanguard Hotels Pte. Ltd October 2015 – September 2020

Develop, integrate, design, and implement strategies and technology to maximize overall company IT infrastructure/Systems and to minimize cost through implementation of effective management process and data driven fact-based business decisions. In charge of all ongoing and incoming Hotel Projects in Asia Pacific such as Malaysia, Vietnam, and The Philippines. Coordinate with various parties to include but not limited to Project Management, Infrastructure Design, System Implementation, Telco, Cloud Hosted Systems and ensure full compliance with the requirements and pre-confirmed specifications.

Country Manager (Support and Implementation) Fiesta Pacific Asia Inc.

October 2014 – October 2015

Responsible to implement and install application solutions on the customer's servers, and test production environments. Work onsite and offsite to troubleshoot and diagnose customer reported issues on the different levels of solutions (i.e., Database, Application, Network, Communication, Integration Interfaces Levels, Software Optimization, Application Performance, and performing Debugging Procedures)

Corporate IT Manager
Thunderbird Resorts Inc
January 2010 – September 2014
Corporate IT Manager
Thunderbird Resorts Inc
January 2005 – January 2010

Responsible of overseeing all IT functions of the company not limited to Systems, Network and Servers including Infrastructure for ROHQ and Hotel Properties and Casinos. Aligning IT Infrastructure with current and future business requirements and goals. Managing IT budget, forecast, and enforcing cost-effectiveness. Evaluating risk, developing network recovery and backup processes.



PROFILE

General Manager for Infrastructure and Systems with proven experience in Hospitality Industry for 16 years, with a warm and friendly demeanor always. Punctual problem solver and avid multitasker. Track record of being an essential part of the management team (pre-opening and post-opening) in providing effective solutions that produce immediate impact and contribute to the Hotel's long-term success.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+639173016146 +14075308922

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/leningonzalez-81b864a0/

EMAIL:

<u>lenin.gonzalez@gmail.com</u>

OTHER INFO

347 M. Vicente Street. Dansalan Gardens, Mandaluyong City, Philippines September 25, 1976 Nicaraguan Citizen with Permanent Philippines Resident Visa 13(A) ACR#F0000200948 Assessing and purchasing new and replacement hardware. Assuring that IT activities are within the limits of applicable laws, codes, and regulations. Testing, troubleshooting, and adjusting information systems to operate effectively. Implement security of the network, data and its storage and communication systems.

Operations Manager BPO
GEA de El Salvador S.A. de C.V (El Salvador, Central America)
January 2001 – December 2003
Call Center Agent BPO

GEA de El Salvador S.A. de C.V (El Salvador, Central America) January 2000 – January 2001

Responsible to oversee the operations and to ensure that all the needs of the client are met. Hire, train, prepare, and motivate staff members of the team to provide excellent service to customers. Set objectives, analyze call center metrics, ensure that the company and staff meet goals, and provide reliable, efficient support for customers.

Programmer

Universidad Centroamericana JSC (El Salvador, Central America) January 1998 – December 2000

Responsible to define business requirement documents, conceptualize and develop. Test, analyze and maintain new software applications in support of the achievement of BRD, not limited to writing, coding, testing, and analyzing software programs and applications.

EDUCATION

Universidad Centroamericana José Simeón Cañas (El Salvador, Central America)

December 2003 Bachelor Computer Science

KEY SKILLS AND CHARACTERISTICS

- IT Project Manager
- Infrastructure Design and System Engineering
- Friendly, courteous, and service oriented
- Leadership
- System Integration
- IT Security
- Excellent written and verbal communication
- Recruiting and Hiring Talent
- IT Ecosystems (PMS, CRS, BE, CRM, RMS, Self-Check-In, Electronic Key BLE)
- Team Player
- Hotel Application Development for iOS and Android
- Honesty, Ambition and Strong Work Ethic
- Bilingual (English and Spanish)
- Hotel IT Construction
- Organizational Skills
- ITIL Foundation
- Cloud Environments